[
    {
        "question": "In an examination, there are 100 questions divided into three groups A, B, and C such that each group contains at least one question. It is known that each question in group A carries 1 mark, each question in group B carries 2 marks, and each question in group C carries 3 marks. It is known that the questions in group A together carry at least 60% of the total marks. If group B contains 23 questions, then how many questions are there in group C?",
        "questionId": "9b8dec7cddbd4dcea38ec92ce42b0bee",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "4",
                "optionId": "e48c85689dc34af38de99b5e1bcad57d"
            },
            {
                "option": "2",
                "optionId": "0de26e055759457ab2bb20e0fdbd3e90"
            },
            {
                "option": "1",
                "optionId": "7a7fab9358454bb59fb6e333b540e721"
            },
            {
                "option": "Cannot be determined",
                "optionId": "883c5f85320b480aa3eecba41bddc819"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "7a7fab9358454bb59fb6e333b540e721",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "The sides of a pentagonal field (not regular) are 1737 meters, 2160 meters, 2358 meters, 1422 meters, and 2214 meters respectively. Find the greatest length of the tape by which the five sides may be measured completely.",
        "questionId": "1e4357f320d74712a0a93d16fb5c8a57",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "7",
                "optionId": "374b4ddfb6aa41f78cbc64e514c27cde"
            },
            {
                "option": "13",
                "optionId": "b84d6bbdccd140368df911a2f09ccf47"
            },
            {
                "option": "11",
                "optionId": "054dfae693b240cbb687c598f7675b2d"
            },
            {
                "option": "9",
                "optionId": "cca766aa5933489ab9f3aca21e61c933"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "cca766aa5933489ab9f3aca21e61c933",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "A student took five papers in an examination, where the full marks were the same for each paper. His marks in these papers were in the proportion of 6:7:8:9:10. In all papers together, the candidate obtained 60% of the total marks. Then, the number of papers in which he got more than 50% marks is:",
        "questionId": "c88c3716f5d447038ca34bbd37adbd0b",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "1",
                "optionId": "3b493bd9e89f460c9a5a7d2406909164"
            },
            {
                "option": "3",
                "optionId": "96cd9c59414f423c8a6738f645021fa4"
            },
            {
                "option": "4",
                "optionId": "ff97def756f74868ae79115d38c39f28"
            },
            {
                "option": "5",
                "optionId": "b49ea031d284480b84cc1289ac18ac82"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "ff97def756f74868ae79115d38c39f28",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "An empty fuel tank of a car was filled with A type petrol. When the tank was half-empty, it was filled with B type petrol. Again when the tank was half empty, it was filled with A type petrol. When the tank was half-empty again, it was filled with B type petrol. What is the percentage of A type petrol at present in the tank?",
        "questionId": "b38ea6ff6a4947eabc654ef01a0dc319",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "33.5%",
                "optionId": "51f6d59549254f4198139e4fd7c3fba3"
            },
            {
                "option": "37.5%",
                "optionId": "149055ecdf8a43b1915b2bdd68a9f7c3"
            },
            {
                "option": "40%",
                "optionId": "db0cc04661c5437d8e6eec57a6dc89d4"
            },
            {
                "option": "50%",
                "optionId": "1d161cc00e924619a13dae3ff3285954"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "149055ecdf8a43b1915b2bdd68a9f7c3",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "A batsman scored 110 runs which included 3 boundaries and 8 sixes. What percent of his total score did he make by running between the wickets?",
        "questionId": "dda9e5ab0ee744778d764f808e77574b",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "45%",
                "optionId": "a0187396c28b4d43877b1b9c3b8adf56"
            },
            {
                "option": "45 5/11%",
                "optionId": "46f934136c1b43bf8f6b23a0e4dc93bb"
            },
            {
                "option": "54 6/11%",
                "optionId": "44bee0a78923437d89272da56d1dcb1f"
            },
            {
                "option": "55%",
                "optionId": "839488824c90481b896982770aafb0fe"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "46f934136c1b43bf8f6b23a0e4dc93bb",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "A litre of water is evaporated from 6 litres of sugar solution containing 4% of sugar. Find the percentage of sugar in the remaining solution.",
        "questionId": "3e10f6acc428468db8585dcdf397634f",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "3.33",
                "optionId": "72e596c011d94410a24d5e1f5f457e18"
            },
            {
                "option": "4.80",
                "optionId": "3a0c44ada5f24061bb3aec1d1f74daef"
            },
            {
                "option": "4",
                "optionId": "a03e76f1c4cf41578ad8307d5fe23d63"
            },
            {
                "option": "5",
                "optionId": "52009783a3ec44838bf0820805631537"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "3a0c44ada5f24061bb3aec1d1f74daef",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "If A: B = 2: 3 and B: C = 4: 5 then C: A is",
        "questionId": "e4e74e0a5e5a4cdd8c62efec41efe77f",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "15: 8",
                "optionId": "6638e23064d3472580752677593ef9b9"
            },
            {
                "option": "12: 10",
                "optionId": "8699ea627f824c1a8ecf6d5809133fcb"
            },
            {
                "option": "8: 5",
                "optionId": "e6201309c2a841a49864af6ccffd55ee"
            },
            {
                "option": "8: 15",
                "optionId": "29d7f260d7864cbf86f719bd83076cf6"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "6638e23064d3472580752677593ef9b9",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "An empty fuel tank of a car was filled with A type petrol. When the tank was half-empty, it was filled with B type petrol. Again when the tank was half empty, it was filled with A type petrol. When the tank was half-empty again, it was filled with B type petrol. What is the percentage of A type petrol at present in the tank?",
        "questionId": "b38ea6ff6a4947eabc654ef01a0dc319",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "33.5%",
                "optionId": "51f6d59549254f4198139e4fd7c3fba3"
            },
            {
                "option": "37.5%",
                "optionId": "149055ecdf8a43b1915b2bdd68a9f7c3"
            },
            {
                "option": "40%",
                "optionId": "db0cc04661c5437d8e6eec57a6dc89d4"
            },
            {
                "option": "50%",
                "optionId": "1d161cc00e924619a13dae3ff3285954"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "149055ecdf8a43b1915b2bdd68a9f7c3",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the price of petrol increases by 25% and Raj intends to spend only an additional 15% on petrol, then by what percent will he reduce the quantity of petrol purchased?",
        "questionId": "4078bf824b7e4356a0c8002a3d3668e3",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "10%",
                "optionId": "858179db04924481827755e02e82a7f6"
            },
            {
                "option": "12%",
                "optionId": "144e094e4fcc4a5baf0af446a78424f6"
            },
            {
                "option": "8%",
                "optionId": "6b72e027dcd44139952b28e0dd6eb995"
            },
            {
                "option": "6.67%",
                "optionId": "5cc599c5147047c09eaaac6d4046a691"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "6b72e027dcd44139952b28e0dd6eb995",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anup and Balaji have monthly incomes in the ratio 5: 6 and monthly expenditures in the ratio 3: 4. If they save Rs 1800 and Rs. 1600 respectively, find the monthly income of Balaji?",
        "questionId": "c8a9bf5d39f844928c59dd50c1bf8cd2",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 3400",
                "optionId": "450a8791c19a4269958c5d05d5141118"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 2700",
                "optionId": "3ddcb96a35b14838bfec9944fca65348"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 1720",
                "optionId": "eefdce2d1eb5491a867317936514ca4e"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 7200",
                "optionId": "e1de7ff93c4540a48f92e54949c454ce"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "e1de7ff93c4540a48f92e54949c454ce",
        "center": "IIT Pallakad"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an examination, Ramesh scored 20% less than Suresh and 20% more than Mahesh. How much percentage is Mahesh's score less than/more than Suresh's score?",
        "questionId": "e24b5b1175cf431eac71d45a4c80c438",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "33.33%",
                "optionId": "9106cb17d795498297268ded499cf543"
            },
            {
                "option": "50%",
                "optionId": "ecdc356da6a04743b34557692ce277fb"
            },
            {
                "option": "42.85%",
                "optionId": "cfcd60687d2a4754ae8b25424f418d63"
            },
            {
                "option": "None of these",
                "optionId": "9b2502092da8480a9a8d613f0e6ad2e4"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "9106cb17d795498297268ded499cf543",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "The third proportional to 1 and 2 is",
        "questionId": "c5eed63125554c62b7a54a7767d3e1ec",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "2",
                "optionId": "b32b3e7669d24afca86796622d09c24d"
            },
            {
                "option": "3",
                "optionId": "fc4d1f45ef564da09c9cb357b95bea2e"
            },
            {
                "option": "4",
                "optionId": "1ef6e9b6c239436a8e8b923aab3938fb"
            },
            {
                "option": "1",
                "optionId": "07245bb1afd642c0bf7a78754026cafd"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "1ef6e9b6c239436a8e8b923aab3938fb",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the units digit of the expression 11\u00b9 + 12\u00b2 + 13\u00b3 + 14\u2074 + 15\u2075 + 16\u2076.",
        "questionId": "a7299481762249c38a7e6fad289d4b20",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "1",
                "optionId": "36d002b916ba4128ae14afd2c36d7c46"
            },
            {
                "option": "9",
                "optionId": "e5d04abf47b14ae88f76ef3a7b0581f3"
            },
            {
                "option": "7",
                "optionId": "fa44537cc5c24450abe5f01abb4ddb3f"
            },
            {
                "option": "0",
                "optionId": "81aa3a586ffc4f5da0e3471b946ff6e1"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "e5d04abf47b14ae88f76ef3a7b0581f3",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Incomes of Abhi and Banu are in the ratio 4: 3 and their annual expenses in the ratio 3: 2. If each save Rs. 60,000 at the end of the year, the annual income of Abhi is:",
        "questionId": "e36460bfbc7c44f7b0c7766651db8ca5",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 1, 20,000",
                "optionId": "54a00dfed4db4de7b2b0226132c2e07f"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 1, 50,000",
                "optionId": "4345c89636884291a34e00c73d0f244d"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 2, 40,000",
                "optionId": "5652a6a522af46ac83cdd801655b446f"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 3, 60,000",
                "optionId": "2d459ca25dda4b76a115a47cc5e53c56"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "5652a6a522af46ac83cdd801655b446f",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anil spends 40% of his income on rent, 30% of the remaining on medicines, and 20% of the remaining on education. If he saves Rs. 840 every month, then find his monthly salary.",
        "questionId": "7905dc8a65d64e04a4d9bd6908759a19",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs.1800",
                "optionId": "2c7a8fe3d0cf4c00a05d89b611b926d0"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs.2000",
                "optionId": "6bec525410f84ebdabc75efe03249470"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs.2200",
                "optionId": "51dd960d7b7042fab91f5d9f33ab95a0"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs.2500",
                "optionId": "8a56513a1eaa483c832b5ed9f50f17b7"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "8a56513a1eaa483c832b5ed9f50f17b7",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the maximum power of 18 in 200!.",
        "questionId": "9dea9879b90f4ab7b212c3a4db3f50fa",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "90",
                "optionId": "2d20dc823a8a4222bfa5c8bc5a4f8fe6"
            },
            {
                "option": "38",
                "optionId": "7e42e1daac3444be9887561f41083837"
            },
            {
                "option": "11",
                "optionId": "6204d0212ad046f4912bf23fe8687b8f"
            },
            {
                "option": "48",
                "optionId": "5b340d9a9fb646708fb45ed2d37ced5c"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "5b340d9a9fb646708fb45ed2d37ced5c",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "The fourth proportional to 12, 14, and 18 is?",
        "questionId": "e5a8b29b037b448391c27670433b2012",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "21",
                "optionId": "53191d5c7ee047cab7a322e647903296"
            },
            {
                "option": "20",
                "optionId": "9ce1d86f6db040c78385a59ce986a5d8"
            },
            {
                "option": "22",
                "optionId": "00140887fda342f398f9901e7e7f3534"
            },
            {
                "option": "28/3",
                "optionId": "b280af3508844204957d5bcd0e2f7f0e"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "53191d5c7ee047cab7a322e647903296",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "The speeds of three trucks are in the ratio 3: 4: 5. The ratio between the times taken by these cars to travel the same distance is",
        "questionId": "a5c76364aef2452abb78390a7b0b35a0",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "12: 15: 20",
                "optionId": "ce0d852e23704df6962d07150e869497"
            },
            {
                "option": "20: 15: 12",
                "optionId": "ea74c56488074c5eb221b89089ba0278"
            },
            {
                "option": "5: 4: 3",
                "optionId": "e4bb2dd963de45f2ac407cb09a45180c"
            },
            {
                "option": "25: 16: 9",
                "optionId": "4718009acba34366bd269d263a7fb01c"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "ea74c56488074c5eb221b89089ba0278",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "The present ratio of ages of Alpha and Beta is 4: 5. 18 years ago, this ratio was 11: 16. Find the sum of their ages 18 years ago.",
        "questionId": "b2429e081a7943b9a42ae8df6faf99c6",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "90 years",
                "optionId": "34e51b325dec4badb6f4eac834df25eb"
            },
            {
                "option": "54 years",
                "optionId": "93d786e9e588458fa04cd3446a840b9a"
            },
            {
                "option": "64 years",
                "optionId": "ea3dfb10b4804d708703c22ee0eb952a"
            },
            {
                "option": "66 years",
                "optionId": "b852b51da9894ca7a189cdffca0fc7b3"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "93d786e9e588458fa04cd3446a840b9a",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the maximum value of n such that 157! is perfectly divisible by 10\u207f.",
        "questionId": "62ce10f986b348e39c6be5a8c1a7c7ff",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "37",
                "optionId": "b83dc65494134a1fbeae996e653d309b"
            },
            {
                "option": "38",
                "optionId": "45e2b94cbb2846d7a9563c65430fec4b"
            },
            {
                "option": "36",
                "optionId": "da2472c090d5496cb24bf9553fb5bdf1"
            },
            {
                "option": "35",
                "optionId": "6e79b20da4a0449fb367debf0407d0d5"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "45e2b94cbb2846d7a9563c65430fec4b",
        "center": "IIT Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rate of increase of the price of sugar is observed to be two percent more than the inflation expressed in percentage. The price of sugar on January 1, 2017 is Rs. 50 per kg. The inflation rates of the years 2017 and 2018 are expected to be 8% each. The expected price of sugar on January 1, 2019 would be:",
        "questionId": "e6503a022f1f4c04a12e654e2a6296a2",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 53.50",
                "optionId": "480451d0487b42c69eb5644188ed0f24"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 58.32",
                "optionId": "67b679cba9fb49b7850b3d54d09ecbb8"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 60.50",
                "optionId": "42b962c7ea2a42cd89e8680a55217c71"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 60.60",
                "optionId": "383297157a7849a1bcd4db8b862a67c4"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "42b962c7ea2a42cd89e8680a55217c71",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "If the radius of the circle is increased by 5%, then the area is increased by:",
        "questionId": "edcdf6d6c6514aca8e329d047e5c4154",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "10.20%",
                "optionId": "f76a9ca5e10c481a861e625dfde173ef"
            },
            {
                "option": "10.22%",
                "optionId": "854e12d13127447da2da00ca8e9c9f7d"
            },
            {
                "option": "10.24%",
                "optionId": "59c6191b9d204d1e95f4347d3fa76b9a"
            },
            {
                "option": "10.25%",
                "optionId": "2d808a7b837448c1926cbdb4cc10ef81"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "2d808a7b837448c1926cbdb4cc10ef81",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Four numbers in the ratio 1: 3: 4: 7 add up to give a sum of 105, find the value of second biggest number.",
        "questionId": "6970d1030b2a42908c9c1993bf92d6b4",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "35",
                "optionId": "f193cd4d3450431c9415245c3efe625e"
            },
            {
                "option": "28",
                "optionId": "be86ffdbd7af46fea31e5d31d66f4ff3"
            },
            {
                "option": "42",
                "optionId": "598cd2cc27a04064ae115be59e5113b3"
            },
            {
                "option": "63",
                "optionId": "1cc63968671d4469885d20c50e533435"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "be86ffdbd7af46fea31e5d31d66f4ff3",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two-fifth of one-third of three-seventh of a number is 15. What is 40% of that number?",
        "questionId": "d74e925058d94bc08b9a35d91dc49ea4",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "100",
                "optionId": "06286e5a2772421483afc271f4ec489b"
            },
            {
                "option": "105",
                "optionId": "5c23ada9064e4bdcb3ed34e0ec82d56e"
            },
            {
                "option": "125",
                "optionId": "84eac6b50b684fd3b4c1576dd3666d3b"
            },
            {
                "option": "150",
                "optionId": "3ce2dc6f5f0347ddbcb84983522fc5e9"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "5c23ada9064e4bdcb3ed34e0ec82d56e",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following can be a number divisible by 24?",
        "questionId": "18bcbdd8830e48d98e18645796b8ef11",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "432,15604",
                "optionId": "f7d6330a99b24de3b225b792f7427068"
            },
            {
                "option": "2561284",
                "optionId": "ae125f1087b746e5a1702bd6f29128a0"
            },
            {
                "option": "1362480",
                "optionId": "9cd99216a21f4105883aa30d73fa716f"
            },
            {
                "option": "All of these",
                "optionId": "38b40bfb31494e1aa67cf3e9ec0eab46"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "9cd99216a21f4105883aa30d73fa716f",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "If x = (16\u00b3 + 17\u00b3 + 18\u00b3 + 19\u00b3), then x when divided by 70 leaves a remainder of:",
        "questionId": "d8712e33c59f497eae21bf88bf12b56b",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "0",
                "optionId": "8a4db639b8f74aa4a522ac9fafa99095"
            },
            {
                "option": "1",
                "optionId": "1b0a0d5e8dc745938c2539cd01f0df91"
            },
            {
                "option": "69",
                "optionId": "66f0d2b7534a4b79b30e7f07b58693ad"
            },
            {
                "option": "35",
                "optionId": "a3ab68b718254089b19b99baf280c88a"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "8a4db639b8f74aa4a522ac9fafa99095",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the maximum power of 18 in 200!.",
        "questionId": "9dea9879b90f4ab7b212c3a4db3f50fa",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "90",
                "optionId": "2d20dc823a8a4222bfa5c8bc5a4f8fe6"
            },
            {
                "option": "38",
                "optionId": "7e42e1daac3444be9887561f41083837"
            },
            {
                "option": "11",
                "optionId": "6204d0212ad046f4912bf23fe8687b8f"
            },
            {
                "option": "48",
                "optionId": "5b340d9a9fb646708fb45ed2d37ced5c"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "5b340d9a9fb646708fb45ed2d37ced5c",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a survey of political preferences, 78% of those were in favor of at least one of the proposals: I, II, and III. 50% favored proposal I, 30% favored proposal II, and 20% favored proposal III. If 5% favored all three proposals, what percentage of those asked favored more than one of the three proposals?",
        "questionId": "5caea09e9e04423f8253702374c24bc2",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "10",
                "optionId": "227fc1923d1c47d5aef1667acc0e3b43"
            },
            {
                "option": "12",
                "optionId": "6d836bc71f6c4533bb788ce263411f59"
            },
            {
                "option": "17",
                "optionId": "f26b50e701f4441784374a14fd0ef266"
            },
            {
                "option": "22",
                "optionId": "d470d0c1089b4982bcb70be10387c409"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "f26b50e701f4441784374a14fd0ef266",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the number of divisors of 1728.",
        "questionId": "8e3238d6ed474a64ab18150ede22d666",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "18",
                "optionId": "5f64a212389f405e81660c7aa7af4502"
            },
            {
                "option": "30",
                "optionId": "7ae34ff1fe4e4160afc34b5b5d33f1aa"
            },
            {
                "option": "28",
                "optionId": "b15e5f687fde45728af6ad9113bf3da1"
            },
            {
                "option": "20",
                "optionId": "26a5e035fe564338b12c20bcb95cf9b4"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "b15e5f687fde45728af6ad9113bf3da1",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the end of year 2008, S bought nine dozen goats. Henceforth, every year he added p% of the goats at the beginning of the year and sold q% of the goats at the end of the year where p > 0 and q > 0. If S had nine dozen goats at the end of the year 2017, after making the sales for that year, which of the following is true?",
        "questionId": "9ebbf4d4388c4b629e157af5748e5e16",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "p = q",
                "optionId": "d87c718e8524493ebc2c5e8504191406"
            },
            {
                "option": "p < q",
                "optionId": "d830d30d5bb540abbb4c88a5e358fa54"
            },
            {
                "option": "p > q",
                "optionId": "3460d1f377164436b8986e12112e2e20"
            },
            {
                "option": "p = q/2",
                "optionId": "153cde84c1ba4cb0a921cfb1c9bb47b4"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "3460d1f377164436b8986e12112e2e20",
        "center": "IIT Delhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Anup and Balaji have monthly incomes in the ratio 5: 6 and monthly expenditures in the ratio 3: 4. If they save Rs 1800 and Rs. 1600 respectively, find the monthly income of Balaji?",
        "questionId": "c8a9bf5d39f844928c59dd50c1bf8cd2",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 3400",
                "optionId": "450a8791c19a4269958c5d05d5141118"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 2700",
                "optionId": "3ddcb96a35b14838bfec9944fca65348"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 1720",
                "optionId": "eefdce2d1eb5491a867317936514ca4e"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 7200",
                "optionId": "e1de7ff93c4540a48f92e54949c454ce"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "e1de7ff93c4540a48f92e54949c454ce",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rate of increase of the price of sugar is observed to be two percent more than the inflation expressed in percentage. The price of sugar on January 1, 2017 is Rs. 50 per kg. The inflation rates of the years 2017 and 2018 are expected to be 8% each. The expected price of sugar on January 1, 2019 would be:",
        "questionId": "e6503a022f1f4c04a12e654e2a6296a2",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 53.50",
                "optionId": "480451d0487b42c69eb5644188ed0f24"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 58.32",
                "optionId": "67b679cba9fb49b7850b3d54d09ecbb8"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 60.50",
                "optionId": "42b962c7ea2a42cd89e8680a55217c71"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 60.60",
                "optionId": "383297157a7849a1bcd4db8b862a67c4"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "42b962c7ea2a42cd89e8680a55217c71",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "The rate of increase of the price of sugar is observed to be two percent more than the inflation expressed in percentage. The price of sugar on January 1, 2017 is Rs. 50 per kg. The inflation rates of the years 2017 and 2018 are expected to be 8% each. The expected price of sugar on January 1, 2019 would be:",
        "questionId": "e6503a022f1f4c04a12e654e2a6296a2",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 53.50",
                "optionId": "480451d0487b42c69eb5644188ed0f24"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 58.32",
                "optionId": "67b679cba9fb49b7850b3d54d09ecbb8"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 60.50",
                "optionId": "42b962c7ea2a42cd89e8680a55217c71"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 60.60",
                "optionId": "383297157a7849a1bcd4db8b862a67c4"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "42b962c7ea2a42cd89e8680a55217c71",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "A college has raised 75% of the amount it needs for a new building by receiving an average donation of Rs. 600 from the people already solicited. The people already solicited represent 60% of the people the college intended to ask for donations. If the college is to raise exactly the amount needed for the new building, what should be the average donation from the remaining people to be solicited?",
        "questionId": "756a99da72ee429c8c681e67cd49ed50",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 300",
                "optionId": "40c535f201054ecbbecd8c4480ad906f"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 250",
                "optionId": "706d7487914d4fd6afcf6ab45cb312e2"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 400",
                "optionId": "c04fa4bbdaf44f1b8e2fcdff17a7a211"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 500",
                "optionId": "c803f639d286415ca697cbc4b1a1a99f"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "40c535f201054ecbbecd8c4480ad906f",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the number of divisors of 1728.",
        "questionId": "8e3238d6ed474a64ab18150ede22d666",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "18",
                "optionId": "5f64a212389f405e81660c7aa7af4502"
            },
            {
                "option": "30",
                "optionId": "7ae34ff1fe4e4160afc34b5b5d33f1aa"
            },
            {
                "option": "28",
                "optionId": "b15e5f687fde45728af6ad9113bf3da1"
            },
            {
                "option": "20",
                "optionId": "26a5e035fe564338b12c20bcb95cf9b4"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "b15e5f687fde45728af6ad9113bf3da1",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the least number which when doubled will exactly be divisible by 12, 14, 18, and 22?",
        "questionId": "27d5d31e71c2480faf03fd17191d19fe",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "2772",
                "optionId": "8017a33fb9084e9facaae4d0ff4608e3"
            },
            {
                "option": "1216",
                "optionId": "1b3b40666719414d8e69243dfa069ccc"
            },
            {
                "option": "1286",
                "optionId": "a68b737dfbbe4ff1bd6f29c02326dd45"
            },
            {
                "option": "1386",
                "optionId": "5ffcd66a27c4455782630450572b9b00"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "a68b737dfbbe4ff1bd6f29c02326dd45",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rs. 53 is divided among Alex, Bella, and Charles such that Alex's share is Rs. 7 more than Bella's share and Bella's share is Rs. 8 more than Charles's share. The ratio of their shares is:",
        "questionId": "55a74e62c40e4a6b9da5a41f1125ae68",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "16: 9: 18",
                "optionId": "c0beceb496ee4581b419f463f13a91c9"
            },
            {
                "option": "25: 18: 10",
                "optionId": "1661f2155e8544e2a626de701d89fa37"
            },
            {
                "option": "18: 25: 10",
                "optionId": "659bdd21d3b94b19992a1da773c22c14"
            },
            {
                "option": "15: 8: 30",
                "optionId": "7cf0dd4fd1e641ed8a3505cea3a9e40a"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "1661f2155e8544e2a626de701d89fa37",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "The least number which should be added to 28523 so that the sum is exactly divisible by 3, 5, 7, and 8 is:",
        "questionId": "ae10018a09df4a309fab8f15df780c60",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "41",
                "optionId": "2adecc2237134b34aa0b1d4a51a5345d"
            },
            {
                "option": "42",
                "optionId": "72ab02b35a5745ad86ddf57e924409d5"
            },
            {
                "option": "32",
                "optionId": "6946b3998e5e465d88e24d9ecacef260"
            },
            {
                "option": "37",
                "optionId": "f08dd5f6131c4680947f69c281a88bc9"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "f08dd5f6131c4680947f69c281a88bc9",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "In an election with 2 candidates P & Q, 5/7 of the voters promise to vote for P and the rest promised to vote for Q. Of these, on the last day 15% of the voters went back of their promise to vote for P and 25% of voters went back of their promise to vote for Q, and P lost by 2 votes. Then, the total number of voters is:",
        "questionId": "62367569bd1d491b89f24faf861c6559",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "100",
                "optionId": "9bbaae8c96cc47bfb833e0f9f2f8b856"
            },
            {
                "option": "110",
                "optionId": "3827b7abfc5345d9bdcb93ce01fae1e3"
            },
            {
                "option": "90",
                "optionId": "c0f1e6f40e1244968903342e36d1ec80"
            },
            {
                "option": "95",
                "optionId": "575c73aadd07453a8ff40bfd2d80a980"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "9bbaae8c96cc47bfb833e0f9f2f8b856",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "The profit made by a company in the present year is 20 lakhs. Two years ago, the profit made by the same company was 16 lakhs. What is the percentage change in the profit made by the company?",
        "questionId": "f3773d8b4e5b4f96888dd56a437dfee4",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "20%",
                "optionId": "a0831fd6a72945bd9be0d9087eead0f9"
            },
            {
                "option": "25%",
                "optionId": "a9d4d8370b8440d2b94d11abd198e747"
            },
            {
                "option": "33.33%",
                "optionId": "d9ec79e57c624b70a61765ff9ac12500"
            },
            {
                "option": "None of these",
                "optionId": "85eca15f6d02443db755784ce650b5d8"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "a9d4d8370b8440d2b94d11abd198e747",
        "center": "IIT Madras"
    },
    {
        "question": "A college has raised 75% of the amount it needs for a new building by receiving an average donation of Rs. 600 from the people already solicited. The people already solicited represent 60% of the people the college intended to ask for donations. If the college is to raise exactly the amount needed for the new building, what should be the average donation from the remaining people to be solicited?",
        "questionId": "756a99da72ee429c8c681e67cd49ed50",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "Rs. 300",
                "optionId": "40c535f201054ecbbecd8c4480ad906f"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 250",
                "optionId": "706d7487914d4fd6afcf6ab45cb312e2"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 400",
                "optionId": "c04fa4bbdaf44f1b8e2fcdff17a7a211"
            },
            {
                "option": "Rs. 500",
                "optionId": "c803f639d286415ca697cbc4b1a1a99f"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "40c535f201054ecbbecd8c4480ad906f",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "A bag contains 50 paise, 25 paise and 10 paise coins in the ratio 5: 9: 4 amounting to Rs. 206. The total number of 25 and 10 paise coins is:",
        "questionId": "0ab1c350dffb4752a9e08cd92f6be6b5",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "200",
                "optionId": "a85a6fedb3c2409dacf7e4398c816899"
            },
            {
                "option": "360",
                "optionId": "162b284355f442f9be0424335c747bb3"
            },
            {
                "option": "420",
                "optionId": "a37155e13ded4c7780a904a2b9821f8f"
            },
            {
                "option": "520",
                "optionId": "8b05d986a3854e918e7647acb55ce66e"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "8b05d986a3854e918e7647acb55ce66e",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Two-fifth of one-third of three-seventh of a number is 15. What is 40% of that number?",
        "questionId": "d74e925058d94bc08b9a35d91dc49ea4",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "100",
                "optionId": "06286e5a2772421483afc271f4ec489b"
            },
            {
                "option": "105",
                "optionId": "5c23ada9064e4bdcb3ed34e0ec82d56e"
            },
            {
                "option": "125",
                "optionId": "84eac6b50b684fd3b4c1576dd3666d3b"
            },
            {
                "option": "150",
                "optionId": "3ce2dc6f5f0347ddbcb84983522fc5e9"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "5c23ada9064e4bdcb3ed34e0ec82d56e",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the maximum value of n such that 157! is perfectly divisible by 10\u207f.",
        "questionId": "62ce10f986b348e39c6be5a8c1a7c7ff",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "37",
                "optionId": "b83dc65494134a1fbeae996e653d309b"
            },
            {
                "option": "38",
                "optionId": "45e2b94cbb2846d7a9563c65430fec4b"
            },
            {
                "option": "36",
                "optionId": "da2472c090d5496cb24bf9553fb5bdf1"
            },
            {
                "option": "35",
                "optionId": "6e79b20da4a0449fb367debf0407d0d5"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "45e2b94cbb2846d7a9563c65430fec4b",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "If A5377B is divisible by 72 then which of the following will be maximum?",
        "questionId": "22e9641a02c844148f7a08b6057dfdf5",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "A + B + AB",
                "optionId": "fb887d9ab984484d9172dbfec9851e04"
            },
            {
                "option": "3A + 4B",
                "optionId": "01f94c9cb2f6438b8adccb8717c07ec0"
            },
            {
                "option": "2A + 3B",
                "optionId": "e27570e48ec84b5c9019fd86c952bd1e"
            },
            {
                "option": "2AB",
                "optionId": "cdf14a3420c847ceb9a0c3ac8e324e0f"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "cdf14a3420c847ceb9a0c3ac8e324e0f",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "A bag contains 50 paise, 25 paise and 10 paise coins in the ratio 5: 9: 4 amounting to Rs. 206. The total number of 25 and 10 paise coins is:",
        "questionId": "0ab1c350dffb4752a9e08cd92f6be6b5",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "200",
                "optionId": "a85a6fedb3c2409dacf7e4398c816899"
            },
            {
                "option": "360",
                "optionId": "162b284355f442f9be0424335c747bb3"
            },
            {
                "option": "420",
                "optionId": "a37155e13ded4c7780a904a2b9821f8f"
            },
            {
                "option": "520",
                "optionId": "8b05d986a3854e918e7647acb55ce66e"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "8b05d986a3854e918e7647acb55ce66e",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Water tax is increased by 20% but its consumption is decreased by 20%. Then increase or decrease in the expenditure of the money is:",
        "questionId": "3d7abe02c6f049a389258c9f94c7fcf7",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "40%",
                "optionId": "2ea69b52eb464326ade155c36007d330"
            },
            {
                "option": "4%",
                "optionId": "f1ed6b9166b44ffba3ea08d8f17950bb"
            },
            {
                "option": "96%",
                "optionId": "7b46db36f791499fab2a764c04614c01"
            },
            {
                "option": "None of the above%",
                "optionId": "0ca6ba6038cd4f3b8d1a1025db5df4b3"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "f1ed6b9166b44ffba3ea08d8f17950bb",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cost of house rent accounted for 25% of the income of a particular family. If the income gets raised by 20%, then what must be the change in house rent expenditure in percentage point, given that house rent remains unchanged? (approximately)",
        "questionId": "5471d31e68e34f48aa2de000abcd9a5a",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "3.5",
                "optionId": "8bf3f856a16f47a4a7b209a7fc896801"
            },
            {
                "option": "8.33",
                "optionId": "c53c6c53639a4c97ad7c174c6f8b6834"
            },
            {
                "option": "4.16",
                "optionId": "f0aa0a3d86d24259a43c86952579fb4f"
            },
            {
                "option": "5",
                "optionId": "dee8fb3dca1148d7b24fe1927402e306"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "f0aa0a3d86d24259a43c86952579fb4f",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Four numbers in the ratio 1: 3: 4: 7 add up to give a sum of 105, find the value of second biggest number.",
        "questionId": "6970d1030b2a42908c9c1993bf92d6b4",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "35",
                "optionId": "f193cd4d3450431c9415245c3efe625e"
            },
            {
                "option": "28",
                "optionId": "be86ffdbd7af46fea31e5d31d66f4ff3"
            },
            {
                "option": "42",
                "optionId": "598cd2cc27a04064ae115be59e5113b3"
            },
            {
                "option": "63",
                "optionId": "1cc63968671d4469885d20c50e533435"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "be86ffdbd7af46fea31e5d31d66f4ff3",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "The third proportional to 1 and 2 is",
        "questionId": "c5eed63125554c62b7a54a7767d3e1ec",
        "options": [
            {
                "option": "2",
                "optionId": "b32b3e7669d24afca86796622d09c24d"
            },
            {
                "option": "3",
                "optionId": "fc4d1f45ef564da09c9cb357b95bea2e"
            },
            {
                "option": "4",
                "optionId": "1ef6e9b6c239436a8e8b923aab3938fb"
            },
            {
                "option": "1",
                "optionId": "07245bb1afd642c0bf7a78754026cafd"
            }
        ],
        "answer": "1ef6e9b6c239436a8e8b923aab3938fb",
        "center": "IIT Kanpur"
    }
]